Bye-bye. I just got us reservations at Michelle's and tickets to the music band to celebrate
再見。我剛剛在米歇爾餐廳預訂了房間，還有樂隊慶祝活動的門票
our first holiday season as a betrothed couple.
我們作為訂婚夫婦的第一個假期。
Betrothed.
訂婚了。
Betrothed couple.
已訂婚的夫婦。
Hey.
嘿。
Huh?
啊？
Oh.
哦。
Pheebs?
菲比斯？
Huh?
啊？
Skull?
顱骨？
Oh, yeah, it's my mom's.
哦，是的，這是我媽媽的。
Oh, my God!
我的天啊！
No, no, no, it's not, it's not my mom.
不，不，不，這不是，這不是我媽。
It belonged to my mom.
它屬於我媽媽。
Yeah, no, she used to put it out every Christmas to remind us that even though it's Christmas,
是的，不，她以前每年聖誕節都會把它拿出來提醒我們，即使是聖誕節，
people still die.
人們仍然會死。
And you can put candy in it.
而且裡面還可以放糖果。
Hey.
嘿。
Hey, I just found out I get Ben for the holidays this year.
嘿，我剛剛發現今年我和本一起度假。
Oh, that's great.
哦，那太好了。
Are you gonna dress up as Santa?
你要打扮成聖誕老人嗎？
Nope.
沒有。
I mean, I know Susan does every year,
我的意思是，我知道蘇珊每年都會這樣做，
but I think I want to take this year to teach him all about Hanukkah.
但我想我想利用今年的時間教他有關光明節的一切。
And maybe I could teach Ben about the Christmas skull and how people die.
也許我可以教本聖誕頭骨和人們如何死亡的知識。
You may need to use this year to teach Ben about Phoebe.
你可能需要利用今年來向本介紹菲比。
Mm.
毫米。
Hey.
嘿。
Did you know I was in there?
你知道我在裡面嗎？
No.
不。
How long have we been home?
我們回家多久了？
About a half an hour.
大約半小時。
Lovely.
迷人的。
Hey, you know what I was thinking?
嘿，你知道我在想什麼嗎？
When we get married, are you gonna, uh,
當我們結婚時，你會，呃，
change your last name to Bing?
將你的姓氏改為 Bing？
Nope.
沒有。
Why not?
為什麼不呢？
Bing's weird.
賓很奇怪。
Yeah, I know what you mean.
是的，我知道你的意思。
Dillard.
迪拉德。
Oh, hey, you guys.
哦，嘿，你們。
Hey.
嘿。
Guess what?
你猜怎麼著？
My landlord just called, and my apartment's gonna be ready soon,
我的房東剛剛打來電話，我的公寓很快就會準備好
so I guess I'll be moving out.
所以我想我會搬出去。
Aw, Phoebe, I'm gonna miss you.
噢，菲比，我會想念你的。
Yes, you will be very sad.
是的，你會很難過。
All right, well, I gotta go tell Rachel the good news.
好吧，我得去告訴瑞秋這個好訊息了。
Oh, are you guys gonna be living together again?
哦，你們還要再住在一起嗎？
Yeah, why not?
是啊，為什麼不呢？
Well, she's just having so much fun with Joey,
嗯，她只是和喬伊玩得很開心，
I just assumed she'd still be living with him.
我只是以為她仍然和他住在一起。
Why do you think she's having so much fun living with Joey?
你認為為什麼她和喬伊住得這麼開心？
No reason, except she...
沒有理由，除了她…
told me.
告訴我的。
Really? So she said she didn't want to live with me anymore?
真的嗎？所以她說她不想再跟我住在一起了？
No, no, she didn't say that.
不不，她沒這麼說。
I think you should talk to Monica now.
我想你現在應該和莫妮卡談談。
Phoebe, don't worry about it.
菲比，別擔心。
I'm sure she wants to live with you.
我確信她想和你住在一起。
You're sure? You're absolutely sure?
你確定嗎？你絕對確定嗎？
Well, no, but she probably does.
嗯，不，但她可能會。
Probably?
大概？
Yeah, I don't like that word.
是的，我不喜歡這個詞。
I know what probably really means.
我知道可能真正意味著什麼。
Yeah, mm-hmm, yeah.
是的，嗯嗯，是的。
Oh, your mom probably won't kill herself.
哦，你媽媽可能不會自殺。
You know, no, you know.
你知道，不，你知道。
No, the funeral director probably won't hit on you.
不，葬儀社可能不會找你。
Yeah, that nice couple probably will adopt you.
是的，那對好夫婦可能會收養你。
Yeah, okay, I'm sorry.
是的，好吧，對不起。
I'm sorry, but I'm not hanging all my hopes
抱歉，但我不會抱持全部希望
of Rachel and I living together on probably.
雷切爾和我可能住在一起。
You know, you've got to take care of yourself.
你知道，你必須照顧好自己。
This world, you know, history teaches us nothing.
這個世界，你知道，歷史沒有教我們任何事。
Bing doesn't seem so weird now, does it?
Bing 現在看起來不那麼奇怪了，不是嗎？
Hey, great, you're home.
嘿，太好了，你回來了。
Guess what Phoebe got me for Christmas.
猜猜菲比買了什麼聖誕禮物給我。
Drums?
鼓？
No, drums!
不，鼓！
Hi, can we get two burritos to go, please?
嗨，我們可以買兩個墨西哥捲餅嗎？
I'm sorry, but not that sorry,
我很抱歉，但不是那麼抱歉，
because you don't have to live with it.
因為你不必忍受它。
We have a reservation under the name Chandler Bing.
我們以 Chandler Bing 的名義進行了預訂。
Okay, we'll have a table for you in about 45 minutes.
好的，我們將在大約 45 分鐘內為您安排座位。
45 minutes?
45分鐘？
We have tickets to the Music Man at 8.
我們有 8 點音樂人演出的門票。
I'm sorry, Christmas is a very busy time, sir.
抱歉，聖誕節是一個非常忙碌的時期，先生。
Is this because of the burrito thing?
這是因為捲餅的事情嗎？
You need to give him money.
你需要給他錢。
Give him money? It was a joke.
給他錢？這是一個笑話。
No, to get a table.
不，是為了找一張桌子。
Places like this are always shaking you down.
像這樣的地方總是讓你感到震驚。
Everybody wants a payoff.
每個人都希望得到回報。
All right, calm down, O'Malley.
好吧，冷靜點，奧馬利。
I'll slip him some money.
我會給他一些錢。
You've got to be smooth about it.
你必須要圓滑一點。
Hey, I can be smooth.
嘿，我可以很順利。
Listen, we're in a little bit of a hurry,
聽著，我們有點著急，
so if you could get us a table a little quicker,
所以如果你能更快地為我們安排一張桌子的話
I'd appreciate it.
我會很感激。
Of course, sir.
當然，先生。
Okay.
好的。
How'd it go?
怎麼樣？
Had the money in the wrong hand.
錢落到了壞人手裡。
Hey, you don't feel like you're going to throw up, do you?
嘿，你不覺得自己要吐了，是嗎？
No.
不。
Well, I do, so let's...
嗯，我願意，所以讓我們...
So, Ben, you, uh...
所以，本，你，呃...
You know what holiday is coming up, don't you?
你知道什麼假期即將到來，不是嗎？
Christmas.
聖誕節。
Yep, and you know what other holiday is coming up?
是的，你知道還有什麼假期即將到來嗎？
Christmas Eve.
聖誕節前夕。
Yes, but also...
是的，但也...
Christmas Eve.
聖誕節前夕。
Hanukkah?
光明節？
See, you're part Jewish, and Hanukkah is a Jewish holiday.
看，你是猶太人的一部分，光明節是猶太節日。
Santa has rangers that can fly.
聖誕老公公有會飛的護林員。
Right, but on Hanukkah,
是的，但是在光明節，
Hanukkah is the celebration of a miracle.
光明節是對奇蹟的慶祝。
See, years and years ago,
看吧，很多年前，
there were these people called the Maccabees.
這些人被稱為馬卡比人。
Jingle bells, jingle bells.
鈴兒響叮噹，鈴兒響叮噹。
Okay, yes, that's right, yes,
好吧，是的，沒錯，是的，
but on Hanukkah, we sing,
但在光明節，我們唱歌，
♪ Dreidel, dreidel, dreidel, I made you out of clay ♪
♪ 陀螺，陀螺，陀螺，我用黏土做了你 ♪
♪ Rudolph the red-nosed reindeer... ♪
♪ 紅鼻子馴鹿魯道夫... ♪
Okay, it's not a contest.
好吧，這不是一場競賽。
When is Santa coming?
聖誕老公公什麼時候來？
Well, how about this year,
那麼今年呢
instead of Santa,
而不是聖誕老人，
we have fun celebrating Hanukkah?
我們慶祝光明節玩得開心嗎？
No Santa?
沒有聖誕老人嗎？
Was I bad?
我很糟糕嗎？
No, oh, no, no, no, hey,
不，哦，不，不，不，嘿，
you weren't bad, you've been very good, Ben.
你並不壞，你一直都很好，本。
Santa's mad at me.
聖誕老公公對我很生氣。
No, hey, hey, come on.
不，嘿嘿，來吧。
Ben, Santa is not mad at you, okay?
本，聖誕老公公沒有生你的氣，好嗎？
You're his favorite little guy.
你是他最喜歡的小傢伙。
So Santa's coming?
那麼聖誕老公公來了嗎？
Yes!
是的！
Santa's coming!
聖誕老公公來了！
Will he bring me an ant farm?
他會帶給我一個螞蟻農場嗎？
Will you keep it at Mommy's?
你會把它放在媽媽那裡嗎？
Okay.
好的。
Then sure.
那當然可以。
Look, maybe this slipping him money thing
聽著，也許這是騙他錢的事
is not gonna work, you know?
是行不通的，你知道嗎？
Maybe we should just wait.
也許我們應該等待。
You're the one who said you would die
你就是那個說你會死的人
if you didn't see Music Man.
如果你沒有看到音樂人。
I didn't say die.
我沒說死。
I said cry.
我說哭了。
It's easy, just keep it casual.
很簡單，保持隨意即可。
Give him a kind word, shake his hand,
給他一句善意的話，握握他的手，
and give him the money.
並給他錢。
How do you know so much about this?
你怎麼知道這麼多？
I don't know.
我不知道。
Richard used to do it, didn't he?
理查德過去常常這麼做，不是嗎？
He'd be eating our soup right now.
他現在正在吃我們的湯。
Mustache bastard.
小鬍子混蛋。
Okay, those people just left.
好吧，那些人剛離開。
Come on, quick, give them the money.
來吧，快點，把錢給他們。
We'll get their table.
我們會得到他們的桌子。
Excuse me.
打擾一下。
Ah, ha, ha, ha.
啊哈哈哈哈。
So you like the drums?
那你喜歡鼓嗎？
Oh, that's, that's great.
噢，那是，那太好了。
You know, I was worried that, you know,
你知道，我擔心，你知道，
they would create maybe an unbearable
他們可能會造成難以忍受的
living situation, but...
生活狀況，但是…
Okay, well, apparently not, so yay!
好吧，顯然不是，所以耶！
Hey, hey, Deeps, check it out.
嘿，嘿，迪普斯，看看吧。
We already learned a song.
我們已經學了一首歌。
Ready?
準備好？
One, two, three, four.
一、二、三、四。
Tequila!
龍舌蘭酒！
That's fun.
這很有趣。
Here you go.
幹得好。
Thank you.
謝謝。
You got there? Put it there.
你到了嗎？把它放在那裡。
Definitely not easier with coins.
用硬幣絕對不容易。
Thank you.
謝謝。
Hey, hey, hey.
嘿，嘿，嘿。
Here, now I only owe you 49.50.
在這裡，現在我只欠你49.50。
Hey, Pheebs.
嘿，菲比斯。
Hey.
嘿。
If you want to get Joey a Christmas present
如果你想送喬伊聖誕禮物
that disrupts the entire building,
擾亂了整個建築，
why not get him something a little bit more subtle,
為什麼不給他一些更微妙的東西，
like a wrecking ball or a vial of smallpox
就像一個破碎球或一瓶天花
to release in the hallway?
在走廊釋放？
It's not just the drum noise.
這不僅僅是鼓聲。
Every five minutes,
每五分鐘，
Joey throws his sticks in the air,
喬伊將棍子拋向空中，
and I have to hear,
我必須聽到，
Oh, my eye! Oh, God, my eye!
哦，我的眼睛！哦，上帝，我的眼睛！
I mean, it's so annoying.
我的意思是，這太煩人了。
Yes, thank you.
是的，謝謝。
You see, this is how normal people
你看，正常人就是這樣的
are supposed to react to drums.
應該對鼓做出反應。
Phoebe, you got Joey drums to annoy Rachel
菲比，你讓喬伊打鼓來惹惱瑞秋
so she wouldn't want to live there anymore?
所以她不想再住在那裡了？
Maybe on some level.
也許在某種程度上。
Joey, you know that you could just not
喬伊，你知道你不能
throw the sticks up in the air.
將棍子拋向空中。
What is rock and roll about that?
搖滾樂到底是什麼？
Hey, Joey.
嘿，喬伊。
I got you another present.
我又為你準備了一份禮物。
Okay, what is it?
好吧，那是什麼？
Uh, it's a tarantula!
呃，這是一隻狼蛛！
Oh!
哦！
God!
上帝！
Rachel, I'm sorry.
雷切爾，對不起。
What was I thinking,
我在想什麼，
giving Joey this big, gross, scary spider
給喬伊這隻又大又噁心又可怕的蜘蛛
in such a poorly constructed cage?
在這麼簡陋的籠子裡？
What are you talking about?
你在說什麼？
I love them!
我愛他們！
I had a tarantula when I was a kid.
我小時候養過一隻狼蛛。
But it died because my cat ate it.
但它死了，因為我的貓吃了它。
And then, yeah, my cat died.
然後，是的，我的貓死了。
But, Joey, isn't this cool?
但是，喬伊，這不是很酷嗎？
Is it on me?
是在我身上嗎？
I feel like it's on me.
我感覺它在我身上。
Oh, isn't that adorable?
噢，這不是很可愛嗎？
Joey is afraid of the tarantula.
喬伊害怕狼蛛。
Oh, yeah.
哦，是的。
He's so adorable.
他真是太可愛了。
God, he's just so much fun.
天哪，他真是太有趣了。
Joey's the best.
喬伊是最棒的。
I'm glad you're having so much fun here.
我很高興你在這裡玩得很開心。
Whoa, wait, wait.
哇，等等，等等。
What, Phoebe, what's the matter?
菲比，怎麼了？
Our apartment is ready.
我們的公寓已經準備好了。
And that makes you angry because...
這會讓你生氣，因為...
Because you would rather live here with Joey.
因為你寧願和喬伊住在這裡。
Where did you get that?
你從哪裡得到的？
Monica and Chandler said that you were having so much fun here.
莫妮卡和錢德勒說你們在這裡玩得很開心。
And apparently no amount of drums or tarantulas is gonna change that.
顯然，再多的鼓或狼蛛也無法改變這一點。
Phoebe?
菲比？
Hmm?
唔？
Did you get all this stuff for Joey
你買了這些東西給喬伊嗎
to try and drive me out of the apartment?
試著把我趕出公寓？
Honey, if you wanted to do that,
親愛的，如果你想這麼做，
you might as well have just gotten him a fish.
你還不如買條魚給他。
You know how fish freak me out?
你知道魚是如何嚇到我的嗎？
Fish.
魚。
But it wouldn't have mattered anyway, Phoebe.
但無論如何，這都不重要，菲比。
You and I are gonna live together.
你和我要住在一起。
We're roommates. That's the deal.
我們是室友。就是這樣。
Yes, but I wanted you to want to live with me.
是的，但我希望你願意和我住在一起。
But, okay, if you're having so much fun over here...
但是，好吧，如果你在這裡玩得很開心的話...
Oh, it's so much more fun with you.
哦，和你在一起更有趣。
We did have fun, didn't we?
我們確實玩得很開心，不是嗎？
We had so much fun.
我們玩得很開心。
You remember that time we were playing with the Super Bowl
你還記得那次我們參加超級盃比賽
and we accidentally threw it through the window and it broke?
我們不小心把它扔進了窗戶，它就碎了？
I remember paying for the window,
我記得付了窗費
but I don't remember how it broke.
但我不記得它是怎麼壞的。
Yeah, stuff like that.
是的，諸如此類的事情。
Yeah, yeah.
是啊是啊。
Anyway, they say if we want, we could see it tonight.
不管怎樣，他們說如果我們願意的話，我們今晚就可以看到。
Ah, I would love to!
啊，我很願意！
Yay, okay!
耶，好吧！
Great! All right, good!
偉大的！好吧，很好！
Oh, and Monica asked me to make the drumming stop.
哦，莫妮卡讓我停止敲鼓。
Um...
嗯...
Done!
完畢！
Hey.
嘿。
Hello, sir. You here to return those pants?
你好先生。你是來退貨的嗎？
No, these are my pants.
不，這是我的褲子。
Oh. Okay.
哦。好的。
How can I help you?
我怎麼幫你？
Well, um, do you have a Santa outfit left?
嗯，你還有聖誕老人服裝嗎？
Two days before Christmas?
聖誕節前兩天？
Sorry, man. Did you try Costume City?
對不起，夥計。你嘗試過服裝城嗎？
Yeah, yeah, I've tried everywhere.
是啊是啊，我到處都試過了。
Please, please, I mean, I'll pay extra.
拜託，拜託，我的意思是，我會支付額外費用。
Sorry, but I do have 74 of them coming back on the 26th.
抱歉，我確實有 74 個人會在 26 號回來。
Okay, look, do you have anything Christmassy?
好吧，看看，你有什麼聖誕禮物嗎？
I promised my son and I really don't want to disappoint him.
我答應了兒子，我真的不想讓他失望。
Um, come on, you gotta have something.
嗯，來吧，你得有一些東西。
I'm the Holiday Armadillo!
我是假日犰狳！
I'm a friend of Santa's,
我是聖誕老公公的朋友
and he sent me here to wish you a Merry Christmas!
他派我來這裡祝你聖誕快樂！
What happened to Santa, Holiday Armadillo?
聖誕老人，假日犰狳怎麼了？
Santa was unavailable so close to Christmas.
臨近聖誕節，聖誕老公公沒能到場。
Oh, come in, have a seat.
哦，進來吧，坐吧。
You must be exhausted coming all the way from Texas.
你從德州千里迢迢趕來，一定很累了。
Texas?
德克薩斯州？
That's right, Ben.
沒錯，本。
I'm Santa's representative for all the southern states.
我是所有南方各州的聖誕老人代表。
And Mexico!
還有墨西哥！
But Santa sent me here to give you these presents, Ben.
但聖誕老人派我來這裡是為了給你這些禮物，本。
Maybe the lady will help me with these presents.
也許那位女士會幫我買這些禮物。
Wow!
哇！
Wow, thanks!
哇，謝謝！
You're welcome, Ben. Merry Christmas.
不客氣，本。聖誕快樂。
And Happy Hanukkah!
光明節快樂！
Are you for Hanukkah too? Because I'm part Jewish.
你也來光明節嗎？因為我有部分猶太血統。
You are? Me too!
你是？我也是！
Because armadillos also wandered in the desert?
因為犰狳也在沙漠中徘徊？
You want to wander in the hall?
你想在大廳閒晃嗎？
Hey, Ben!
嘿，本！
What if the Holiday Armadillo told you all about the Festival of Lights?
如果節日犰狳告訴你有關排燈節的一切怎麼辦？
Cool!
涼爽的！
Come on, Ben.
來吧，本。
Years and years ago, there were these people called the Maccabees.
許多年前，有一些人被稱為馬卡比人。
Ho, ho, ho! Merry Christmas!
嗬，嗬，嗬！聖誕快樂！
Santa!
聖誕老人！
Hey!
嘿！
What are you doing here, Santa?
你在這裡做什麼，聖誕老人？
Well, I'm here to see my old buddy, Ben.
嗯，我是來看我的老朋友本的。
What are you doing here?
你在這裡做什麼？
Weird... turtle men?
奇怪……龜人？
I'm the Holiday Armadillo!
我是假日犰狳！
Your part Jewish friend!
你的猶太朋友！
You sent me here to give Ben some presents, remember?
你派我來這裡是為了給本一些禮物，記得嗎？
What?
什麼？
Did you bring me any presents, Santa?
聖誕老人，你帶禮物了嗎？
You bet I did, Ben! Put it there!
你打賭我做到了，本！把它放在那裡！
Well, it would have worked this time if his hands weren't so damn small.
好吧，如果他的手不是那麼小的話，這次應該可以成功。
Ho, ho, ho!
嗬，嗬，嗬！
Okay, Ben, why don't you come open some more presents,
好吧，本，為什麼不再開啟一些禮物呢？
and Santa, the Armadillo, and I will have a little talk in the kitchen.
聖誕老公公、犰狳和我會在廚房聊一會兒。
There's a sentence I never thought I'd say.
有句話我從來沒想過會說出來。
What are you doing?
你在幹什麼？
You called everyone and said you were having trouble finding a Santa costume,
你打電話給所有人說你找不到聖誕老人服裝，
so I borrowed one from a guy at work.
所以我跟同事借了一個。
Thank you, but you gotta leave.
謝謝你，但你得走了。
Why?
為什麼？
Because I'm finally getting him excited about Hanukkah!
因為我終於讓他對光明節感到興奮了！
I mean, you're wrecking it!
我的意思是，你正在破壞它！
But I didn't get to shake my belly like a bowl full of jelly!
但我還來不及把肚子像一碗果凍一樣晃來晃去！
I'm sorry, Chandler, but this is really important to me.
對不起，錢德勒，但這對我來說真的很重要。
Okay, fine, I'll give the suit back.
好吧，好吧，我會把衣服還給你。
Hey, you think you can keep it another night?
嘿，你覺得你可以再留一晚嗎？
Santa? Really?
聖誕老人？真的嗎？
Yeah, is that okay?
是啊，這樣可以嗎？
Did your dad ever dress up like Santa?
你爸爸曾經打扮成聖誕老公公嗎？
No.
不。
Then it's okay!
那就沒事了！
Okay, Ben, Santa has to go. Say goodbye!
好吧，本，聖誕老公公得走了。告別！
No, why does he have to go?
不，他為什麼要走？
Because if Santa and the holiday...
因為如果聖誕老人和假期...
Armadillo...
犰狳...
are ever in the same room for too long, the universe will implode!
在同一個房間呆太久，宇宙就會爆炸！
Merry Christmas!
聖誕快樂！
No, why can't the Armadillo leave? I want Santa!
不，為什麼犰狳不能離開？我想要聖誕老人！
Fine, I give up. Santa can stay!
好吧，我放棄了。聖誕老人可以留下來！
Well, I'll stay, but only because I want to hear about Hanukkah.
好吧，我會留下來，但只是因為我想聽聽光明節的事。
Ben, will you sit here with Santa and learn about Hanukkah?
本，你願意和聖誕老人​​一起坐在這裡瞭解光明節嗎？
Okay, Santa!
好吧，聖誕老人！
All right, it's time for the story of Hanukkah!
好了，現在是光明節故事的時間了！
Years and years ago, there were these people called the Maccabees!
許多年前，有一些人被稱為馬卡比人！
Merry Christmas!
聖誕快樂！
Oh, wow! Look at this place!
哦，哇！看看這個地方！
Oh, this is terrible!
哦，這太可怕了！
Oh, they've made so many changes, I can't even feel my grandmother's presence anymore!
哎喲，變化太大了，我都感覺不到奶奶的存在了！
Oh, new sconces!
哦，新壁燈！
Oh, my God!
我的天啊！
What?
什麼？
Okay, remember how you told me that your grandmother put up that wall to make that into two bedrooms?
好吧，還記得你告訴我你祖母把那堵牆建起來，把它變成兩間臥室嗎？
Yeah.
是的。
And remember how you always said you were afraid that the landlord would find out and then tear it down?
還記得你總是說你害怕房東發現然後把它拆掉嗎？
Yeah.
是的。
Do you really not know where I'm going with this?
你真的不知道我要說的是什麼嗎？
No, of course I do!
不，我當然願意！
Okay.
好的。
What?
什麼？
It left! It's one huge room!
它離開了！這是一間很大的房間！
Oh, no!
哦，不！
Wow!
哇！
See?
看？
Well, I guess we'll just have to put the wall back up.
好吧，我想我們只需要把牆重新砌起來就可以了。
You can't, because of the new skylight!
你不能，因為有了新的天窗！
There's a skylight?
有天窗嗎？
Wow!
哇！
So, what should we do? Should we start looking for a new place?
那麼，我們該做什麼呢？我們應該開始尋找新的地方嗎？
You know, I'm sensing that my grandmother would not be comfortable with that.
你知道，我感覺到我的祖母對此會感到不舒服。
Oh, yeah? Starting to feel her again there, are we?
哦，是嗎？又開始感覺到她在那裡了，是嗎？
A little bit, yeah.
一點點，是的。
Phoebes, is your grandmother maybe saying that you should live here alone?
菲比，你祖母是不是在說你應該一個人住在這裡？
You heard it, too! You have the gift!
你也聽到了！你有禮物！
Phoebe, it's okay! I like living with Joey!
菲比，沒關係！我喜歡和喬伊住在一起！
Are you sure?
你確定嗎？
Oh, please! I hate packing! It's closer to work, and we do have fun!
哦，拜託！我討厭打包！離工作更近了，我們也很開心！
Although, I'm really going to miss living with you.
不過，我真的會想念和你一起生活的日子。
Oh, me too.
哦，我也是。
Oh, oh, wait! Did you hear that? Hear that? Listen!
噢，噢，等等！你聽到了嗎？聽到了嗎？聽！
Huh?
啊？
I'm getting something from your grandmother.
我從你祖母那裡得到一些東西。
She said that since you get to keep the one-bedroom apartment, you should give Rachel the purple chair?
她說既然你可以保留一間單人的公寓，你應該給雷切爾紫色的椅子嗎？
I do not hear that.
我沒有聽到。
Oh, no, wait a minute. Oh, okay. She didn't say chair, she said share.
哦，不，等一下。哦好的。她沒有說椅子，她說的是分享。
You should share the one-bedroom apartment.
你們應該共用一間臥室的公寓。
Oh, the purple chair! No, yeah, I heard that.
哦，紫色的椅子！不，是的，我聽到了。
And the miracle was that that little bit of oil that should have lasted just one day burned for...
奇蹟在於，那一點點本應只持續一天的油燃燒了…
Eight whole days.
整整八天。
That's right, and that's why we celebrate Hanukkah today. The end.
沒錯，這就是我們今天慶祝光明節的原因。結束。
Awesome!
驚人的！
My favorite part was when Superman flew all the Jews out of Egypt.
我最喜歡的部分是超人將所有猶太人帶出埃及。
The armadillo was actually not so thrilled about that part.
犰狳其實對這部分並不那麼興奮。
Why is Santa kissing Aunt Monica?
聖誕老公公為什麼要親吻莫妮卡阿姨？
Because Aunt Monica was very, very good this year.
因為莫妮卡阿姨今年表現得非常非常好。
Okay, Ben, it's time to light the Hanukkah candles!
好吧，本，是時候點燃光明節蠟燭了！
Hey! Oh, wow! Looks like the Easter Bunny's funeral in here.
嘿！哦，哇！看起來復活節兔子的葬禮就在這裡舉行。
Come on, come on. We're lighting the candles. Come on.
來吧，來吧。我們正在點燃蠟燭。快點。
I understand why Superman is here, but why is there a porcupine at the Easter Bunny's funeral?
我明白為什麼超人在這裡，但為什麼復活節兔子的葬禮上有一隻豪豬？
Did you get it?
你收到了嗎？
I got it.
我得到了它。
Is it back in the cage?
它又回到籠子裡了嗎？
It's back in the cage.
它又回到籠子裡了
The cage closed.
籠子關上了。
Joey, will you just come out here and stop being such a baby?
喬伊，你能到這裡來，別再像個小孩了嗎？